

SENIOR TEST CONSULTANT

□ (+46) 73-340 12 29 | soumya.saligram@gmail.com | • Github | • Linkedin

Summary

I am an engineer, with several years of experience within various areas of product testing. I enjoy automating tests, and in the process, refine the product and its value, always, with the end user in focus. Continuously collaborating with developers, product owners, account managers and testers - to best align with the use-case, while at the same time maintaining a high code coverage, are my strengths.

I am working as a **Senior Test Consultant** at **B3 Innovation AB** since January 2021, currently on assignment as Senior QA Test Automation Specialist at **Nasdaq, Stockholm**.

Prior to this I worked in a TestOps role in an internal React Native project, working with Android/iOS testing with Appium, Selenium WebdriverIO, ReactJs application testing with Cypress and Google Firebase integrations, X-Ray-JIRA integration and bitbucket pipelines. I have worked with setting up a Cypress test suite, applied Postman to make manual regression testing faster and repeatable. I am a certified SAFe 5.0 Agilist. I am familiar with post trade solutions and trading platforms in general(With hands-on knowledge of clearing technology for stock exchanges). Ealier in my career, I have worked for several years in industrial automation.

In my upcoming assignments as a senior QA, I look forward to applying my broad experience in various aspects of Quality Assurance, coaching, test planning and driving "shift-left" testability in exciting projects.

Experience _____

NASDAQ Apr 2021 - Current

SENIOR TEST AUTOMATION SPECIALIST

Stockholm

- · Write unit integration, functional integration tests for a complex, functionally extensive API
- · Participate actively in sprint planning, prioritization, identifying regression and baseline testing priorities
- Design, execute manual exploratory, flow, scenario-based tests
- Troubleshoot, debug, fix test flake on CI pipelines
- TestNG, Java 11, Gradle, Jenkins, Kafka

B3 Innovation AB Jan 2021 - Current

SENIOR CONSULTANT

- Write component tests, end-to-end tests for a React Native App
- Setup test, build and deploy dev pipelines
- Contonously improve test environments for best utilization of resources
- Troubleshooting, debugging of mobile testing bottlenecks
- Cypress, ReactJs, ReactNative, Google Firebase, Bitbucket, Appium, Selenium WebdriverIO, Typescript

Cabonline Technologies AB

QA ENGINEER

May 2019 - Current

Stockholm

Stockholm

- Write end-to-end tests for various web products
- Dockerize the test environment for integration into CI pipelines
- Daily monitoring of CI builds for breakages, flaky tests
- Troubleshooting, debugging, optimization of CI/Docker bottlenecks and failures from the build log files
- · Update, track backlog on JIRA
- Cypress, ReactJs, Docker, Jenkins, Loki, e2e testing, visual regression testing

Cinnober Financial Technology AB/NASDAQ

Sep 2017 - May 2019

Stockholm

Stockholm

TEST DEVELOPER

• Writing functional tests for REST APIs

- · Collaborate with developers in the team, for bug fixes or tasks to be automated for the current release and/or patch delivery
- Have the tests integrated to CI pipeline/s for various work flows, as soon as possible
- · Daily monitoring of CI builds for breakages, flaky tests
- Troubleshooting, debugging of CI bottlenecks and failures from the build log files
- · Update, track backlog on JIRA
- Act as scrum master for testing sprints
- Drive consistent good performance on code quality jobs on CI
- JavaSE8, Eclipse, JUnit4, SmartGit, Python3, Confluence, JIRA, SonarCube

Yanzi Networks AB May 2017 - Jul 2017

INTERN

- Testing of a websocket based REST API with Mocha/Chai libraries
- Documenting the API using LaTeX, in a unix environment
- JavaScript(ES6)
- Mocha/Chai/BDD
- REST API/websockets
- LaTeX

Schneider Electric Apr 2012- May 2013

ASSOCIATE LEAD Bengaluru, India

- Worked on improving test automation with TestComplete
- · Worked closely with various scrum teams during user acceptance and release

Honeywell India Technology Labs

Dec 2005 - Mar 2012

SENIOR ENGINEER

Bengaluru, India

- · Define test plans and test specifications for integration, functional and performance testing, execution of test cases
- Root cause analysis and continuous process improvement(Kaizen)

GE Intelligent Systems(Emerson India)

Nov 2003 - Nov 2005

PROJECT ENGINEER

Bengaluru, India

- · Study the design and technical specifications received from customer and understand the process requirements and deliverables
- Develop the main PLC logic using the Ladder language and VB scripting
- Participate in customer interactions, project reviews and software inspection

Education

SAFe 5.0 scaledagile.com/safe-50/

Nov 2020 - Dec 2020 CERTIFICATION

· Certified SAFe 5.0 Agilist (Valid until Dec 2021)

University of Pennsylvania coursera.org

CERTIFICATION Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

• Studied a certification course on Computational Thinking for Problem Solving

Lexicon IT Konsult Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

STUDENT

- JavaSE8
- JavaEE fundamentals
- Spring/Hibernate fundamentals
- Maven fundamentals
- JUnit
- SQL fundamentals
- HTML5/CSS/JavaScript

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

• Eclipse IDE on Linux/Windows

Dayananda Sagar Institute of Engineering

Bengaluru, India

1999 - 2003

Stockholm

• Studied Instrumentation engineering and completed course with excellent grades.

Awards _____

2009	Honeywell, Bravo-Gold:Process Excellence	Bengaluru
2007	Honeywell, ACS Special Award	Bengaluru
2006	Honeywell, Team excellence award	Bengaluru

November 19, 2021 Soumya Prasad · Resume 3